Salissa Hernandez

C: (303) 961-2912 | E: salissa4@gmail.com | Houston, TX 77006 LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/salissah Portfolio: https://salissa4.github.io/Salissa/ GitHub: https://github.com/Salissa4

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Well-qualified Full Stack Developer familiar with a wide range of programming utilities and languages. Knowledgeable of backend and frontend development requirements. Handles any part of the process with ease. Collaborative team player with excellent technical abilities offering 1 year of related experience.

SKILLS

Analysis Business Development Process Improvement

Agile/Scrum Supply chain management Strategic Planning & Critical Thinking

Interpersonal Leadership Client Relationship Management Fluent Spanish

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Advanced ***** JavaScript, React, MERN

Intermediate **** RESTful API, GraphQL, MongoDB

PROJECTS

deadCoder | Github: https://github.com/Salissa4/deadCoder | Deployed: https://deadcoder.herokuapp.com/

- Build a full stack gaming app utilizing MERN stack that allows players to sign up and select from 3 games, keeping track of high scores.
- Technologies for this project used: MERN, React, GraphQL, Node, Express, MongoDB, Mongoose ODM, Javascript, Material UI, Tailwind, and JWT
- Role: Project lead, front-end and back-end programmer

Gypsy | Github: https://github.com/Salissa4/Gypsy | Deployed: https://polar-fortress-17473.herokuapp.com/

- Gypsy allows a user to login/create an account to save desired locations by dropping a pushpin in Austin, Dallas, Houston, saving the coordinates, a name and description
- Technologies: Mysql2, Sequelize, Leaflet, Bcrypt, Eslint, Handlebars, Chalk, Dotenv, Sessions, Javascript, CSS
- Role: Project lead and back-end programmer

Bored NO MO! | Github: https://github.com/Salissa4/BoredNoMo | Deployed:

https://salissa4.github.io/BoredNoMo/

- Interactive front-end application utilizing a third-party web API that recommends activities based on several user inputs: type, price, number of participants and accessibility
- Technologies: HTML, Bulma, CSS, Jquery, Javascript, third-party APIs, Agile Methodology
- Role: Project lead and front-end programmer

EXPERIENCE

Gucci, Operations Manager, Dallas, TX10/2017 to 05/2021Montblanc, Sales Manager, Houston, TX11/2016 to 10/2017BCBGMaxazria, Assistant Manager, Houston, TX09/2015 to 10/2016

EDUCATION

University of Texas Austin – Austin, Texas | Certificate in Full Stack Web Development University of North Texas – Denton, Texas | Bachelor of Science